He saw the world in a way no one could have imagined.
A Beautiful Mind is a drama, romance film directed by Ron Howard.
From the heights of notoriety to the depths of depravity, John Forbes Nash Jr.
experiences it all.
As a brilliant but socially awkward mathematician, he made a groundbreaking discovery
early in his career and stands on the brink of international acclaim.
But as the handsome and arrogant Nash accepts secret work in
cryptography, he becomes entangled in a mysterious conspiracy.
His life takes a nightmarish turn and he soon finds himself on a
painful and harrowing journey of self-discovery.
John Nash, played by Russell Crowe.
Alicia Nash, played by Jennifer Connelly.
William Parcher, played by Ed Harris.
Charles Herman, played by Paul Bettany.
Dr. Rosen, played by Christopher Plummer.
Richard Sol, played by Adam Goldberg.
A Beautiful Mind is a 2001 American biographical drama film about the mathematician John Nash
who won a Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic Sciences, played by Russell Crowe.
The film is directed by Ron Howard based on a screenplay by Akiva
Goldsman, who adapted the 1998 biography by Sylvia Nasar.
In addition to Crowe, the film's cast features Ed Harris, Jennifer Connelly, Paul Bettany, Adam
Goldberg, Judd Hirsch, Josh Lucas, Anthony Rapp, and Christopher Plummer in supporting roles.
The story begins in Nash's days as a brilliant but asocial
mathematics graduate student at Princeton University.
After Nash accepts secretive work in cryptography, he becomes liable to
a larger conspiracy and begins to question his reality.
A Beautiful Mind premiered in Beverly Hills on December 13, 2001 before being released theatrically in the United
States on December 21, 2001, by Universal Pictures and internationally by DreamWorks Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews and went on to gross $316.8 million worldwide against a $58 million budget, and won four Academy
Awards, for Best Picture, Best Director (Ron Howard), Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actress (Jennifer Connelly).
It was also nominated for Best Actor, Best Film Editing,
Best Makeup, and Best Original Score.
The film explores themes of schizophrenia, based on novel or
book, love of one's life, self-discovery, professor.
The tone is emotional and intense.